Curriculum Vitae

Colin Dixon
01/08/1978
272-0133
Chiba-ken, Ichikawa-shi,
Gyotokuekimae, 1-9-14
304 Gyotoku View Heights
Japan
colin.dixon1@hotmail.co.uk
colin.dixon@live.com

Tel: 08043524215

PERSONAL PROFILE

I am an enthusiastic hard working person who always aims high to achieve the goals I am set in work and in life. I have been working the I.T industry now for a many years, during this time I have gained a vast amount experience dealing the business systems, software, hardware desktops and servers that I can now say I am a very confident, competent IT consultant/engineer/ project manager / manager. I have now been in Tokyo for 6 years and my current VISA is permanent.

I have excellent communication skills / team working ability in which I hope you will benefit from. The thing I love about I.T is that you can never know it all and we are always leaning everyday no matter what, there is always something new to learn.

AREAS OF EXPERTISE

Operating Systems - Wintel / MAC

Windows 9x/NT4/2000 / XP/ Vista and server NT /2000 / 2003 / win 7/ server 2008 -2010, Mac OSX, iOS

Software

MS Office 97, 2000, XP and 2003,2007 /2010 MS Exchange 5.5 / 2K/ 2003, 2010 Active Directory, Bloomberg, BES server (all versions), fundmanager, Veritias Backup Exec, PC Anywhere, Mail sweeper, VPN Clients, VNC, Citrix, RDP, Symantec Anti Virus, Norton Internet Security, MacAfee AV, Front Page, IE 6, File Finder, VMvcenter server / Vsphere /Citrix Xendesktop 5.5 plus many more Hardware PC and peripheral configuration, Blackberry, hardware upgrades and repairs, firewalls, server builds including hardware etc.

TCP/ IP, cabling, Wireless routers / routers, Firewalls, DHCP, Windows Peer to Peer etc.

Industry experience

Project Management / IT Consultant, management, Desktop and server support, 1st, 2nd and 3rd line support

Set-up and management of company network operations
People management & leadership skills
Cross functional as leader and team member
Hardware /software field engineer
IT support /system analyst

Other

Currently learning Japanese language
Passionate about superior customer service
Plan, organize and co-ordinate efficiently
Able to use initiative and imagination in problem solving.
Very presentable with excellent communication skills,
Ability to communicate effectively with a wide variety of people.
Enthusiastic and self-motivated, able to adapt, honest and open.

CAREER TO DATE

Company: Credit Suisse – September 2013 to November 2013

Position: Microsoft Exchange 2010 Project Manager / Technical Migration consultant

Job Description and achievements: Collaborate with project managers and team across APAC to migrate all Credit Suisse users successfully to Exchange 2010.

Take an active role in deciding who and when to migrate departments, collaborate and decide methods for certain scenarios in regards to certain departments issues, active support of mass user base after migration group is completed. Technical advice on certain aspects of the migrations and cleanup operations

Company: EIRE Systems K.K Feb 2007 – November 4th 2012

Position: I.T Consultant / Project manager within EIRE systems internal team working direct for EIRE

Systems

Job Description and achievements:

Provide consultation and support for the EIRE systems direct client base within Tokyo Region, provide small projects when requested.

Joint manage internal EIRE systems IT infrastructure

Manage support team when team leader was absent

Project - 4/2011 VDI Project State street capital

My main task in this role was to focus and collaborate / advise on the transition from State Street's current physical IT desktop infrastructure, and migrate to a Virtual desktop infrastructure

After the server infrastructure was built, I was responsible, along with my partner, for creating and administrating 400 + virtual desktops using VMware Virtual Center Server in combination with Citrix Xendesktop 5.5 and migrating user profiles.

My other task was to research and fix any issues we have had with software and hardware. I was also responsible for testing thin client hardware and advising on a suitable device.

Another project that I was involved in was the creation and roll-out of a power saving policy for the whole of the Tokyo office during the Japanese power saving crisis after the 3/11 earthquake.

Along with day to day support queries and research

Project - Large international bank Data center move - Feb 2010 until August 2010

I was joint project manager with a colleague within EIRE Systems looking after a 400 + Server datacenter migration over a period of a few months, in charge of a team of anywhere between 10 and 20 engineers. This involved studying the move plan provided to us by the client, and organizing under guidance from the client, the un-racking of servers, labeling or cables and equipment and organizing the re-racking in the new data center with cabling.

.....

Company: MMR IT LTD -Feb 2006 to Dec 2007

Position: I.T Consultant - Finance Team

Job Description: Provide Project management, technical support and consultation for around 10 hedge funds within London.

Key responsibilities:

- Manage complete IT systems, advise and project manage and install Meet new clients and talk about further development, projects etc.
- look after disaster recovery for my allocated clients
- day to day support
- Manage myself and time bill the customers
- 24 /7 support when needed

As before this job requires all of the below and more. As I step up the ladder in my career my knowledge has improved vastly. In MMR we work very closely as a team and bounce ideas off of each other which is a great benefit to our work and customers. The Customer tells us what they would like to achieve and we

discuss ways, write a proposal and implement it within a time frame. We also support the client, so in a sense I am like the IT manager for a number if clients within the London financial industry. As you probably know it is critical that hedge fund systems are up 24 /7 due to the nature of the work so it is vital we are always one step ahead when thinking about their IT systems.

Overall I have a fantastic trust relationship and technical ability with which my clients trust fully to do the job that they require

.....

Company: Connect Support Services Ltd, UK Sept 2002 - Feb 2006

Position: I.T Support Analyst 3rd Line

Job Description: Provide technical support to second line for 300+ companies, both servers and desktops from head office and onsite.

Key responsibilities:

- Administration of email systems i.e. Exchange 5.5 /2000/ 2003. Pop etc Manage and troubleshoot Internet based resource access, i.e. VPN.
- Recover servers from systems failures for example rebuilds and configuration.
- Liaising with 3rd parties regarding server/ router/ Internet and firewall problems.
- Manage disks and disk volumes on both server and desktop.
- Manage and troubleshoot network protocols TCP/IP and services, for example routers and server connectivity.
- Monitor and optimize system performance and reliability on both servers and desktops. Installations and upgrades of Windows 98, NT, 2000 and XP.
- Install, configure and troubleshoot hardware devices, e.g. hard drives, motherboards, power supplies, video cards, sound cards, CD-ROM drives /burners, modems etc.
- Analysis of calls and improving on performance.
- User training.

This job requires very good communication skills with a very good sea of knowledge; we cover everything from basics like adding printers to advanced work like configuring Active directory and MS exchange. We have to work as part of a close team sharing knowledge all the time to the job done. We deal with over 260 companies, some of which have 6+ servers linked via a WAN with 200+ users. This requires a lot of patience as we are under a great deal of pressure and to deadlines.

Company: CRP Plymouth College September 2001 - August 2002

Position: Field service engineer

Job Description: recondition old PC's and rebuild them, sell them and support them

Key responsibilities:

- Rebuild all sorts of old PC's from parts at HQ from P75's to P400's +
- Be responsible for training more junior engineers in hardware and software
- Make sure all the old parts were sorted with the store room
- All software and hardware support for the machines which are built
- Sales rep for the college i.e. demonstrating to the customers what the machines could do
- PAT testing and general maintenance of all equipment

- Networking around the HQ

This job required a lot of different tasks I was always on the move and always busy but still finding the time for training. I learnt a great deal from this job for which I am grateful i.e. from the very earliest systems to the latest in technology. I learnt excellent customer relation skills and I had to be presentable as I was visiting customer's homes.

Company: ITV Digital January 2001 - March 2001

Position: Customer service representative

Job Description I had to deal with customer billing enquiries over the phone and customer services departments

Company: Derriford Hospital (NHS) September 1998 - December 2000 Position: Medical Laboratory Assistant -Hematologist

Job Description I was responsible for testing blood for all types of problems like cancer, Malaria this I did with specialized equipment, I also worked in blood bank, blood typing people, i.e. A negative etc.

EDUCATION

School Name: Plym view Primary - infant school

.....

Lipson community College (Plymouth)

Qualifications: 9 GCSE's acquired including English and Maths GNVQ Advanced in Information Technology - equivalent to 2 A-levels

Plymouth College of further education

3 city and guilds Computer maintenance and electrical engineering

Self Study

Currently learning Japanese language